Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
John Held papers relating to Mail Art
- Letters, 1973-2008, Series 3:; (Box 1-10; 7.9 linear feet)
  - United States of America (Box 4)
    - Iowa City, Iowa: Lloyd Dunn, 1991-1993, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 46-48)
    - Santa Monica, California: Steve Durland, 1981-1991, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 49-50)
    - San Francisco, California: Mike Dyar (a.k.a. Eat Art), 1991-1995, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 51-52)
    - Los Angeles, California: Jesse Edwards, 1983-1993, undated, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 53-56)
    - New York, New York: John Evans, 1981-1998, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 57-58)
    - Klamuth Falls, Oregon: Walt Evans, 1990, undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Saratoga, California: Arturo Fallico, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Oberlin, Ohio: Harley Francis (a.k.a. Terra Candella), 1985-1989, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 61-63)
    - New York, New York: Peter Frank, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - New York, New York: Franklin Furnace, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - New York, New York: Ken Friedman, 1984-1989, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 66-67)
    - San Francisco, California: William Gaglione (a.k.a. Daddaland), 1979-1996, undated, (5 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 5, Folder 68-72)
    - Santa Monica, California: Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Norwich, New York: Clement Greenberg, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Brookline, Massachusetts: David Greenberger, 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Rensselaer, New York: Mike Gunderloy, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Whittier, California: Laurel Hall (a.k.a. Gorey Laurie), 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Dallas, Texas: Andy Hanson, 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Atlanta, Georgia: Dorothy Harris (a.k.a. Arto Posto), 1990-1995, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
    - Clinton, Connecticut: Margaret Held (Mrs. John Held, Jr.), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Barrytown, New York: Dick Higgins, 1977-1997, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - Thousand Oaks, California: Janet Hofacker (a.k.a. Illustrated Woman), 1982-1994, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
    - Pasadena, California: Judith A. Hoffberg, 1980-1994, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
    - Syracuse, New York: Matt Hogan, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Florence, Alabama: Mimi Holmes (a.k.a. Art Missionary), 1986-1989, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
    - Richmond, Virginia: Davi Det Hompson (David E. Thompson), 1981-1994, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 16-18)
    - Austin, Texas: Honoria (Madelyn Starbuck), 1989-1991, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
    - Rifton, New York: Jennifer Huebert, 1992-1993, undated, (3 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
    - Canton, Texas: Jerry Hunt, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Ukiah, California: Inter-Dada 80, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - San Francisco, California: Inter-Dada 84, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
    - San Francisco, California: Leavenworth Jackson, 1984-1988, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
    - New York, New York: John P. Jacobs (a.k.a. Hype), 1983-1987, undated, (2 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
    - Locust Valley, New York: Ray Johnson, 1977-1990, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 32-35)
    - Fremont, California: Gerald X. Jupitter-Larsen, 1981-1991, undated, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 36-38)
    - Chico, California: Bob Kirkman, 1984-1994, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 39-40)
    - New York, New York: Richard Kostelanetz, 1978-1989, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 41-42)
    - Utica, New York: Jonas Kover (a.k.a. J. K. Post), 1987-1995, undated, (6 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 6, Folder 43-48)
    - Chicago, Illinois: Bradley Lastname, 1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Richmond, Virginia: Gene Laughter, 1984-1986, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 50-52)
    - San Francisco, California: Steven Leiber, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Utica, New York: Toby Levy, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Washington, D.C.: Library of Congress, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Syracuse, New York: Light Work, 1981-1991 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - San Francisco, California: Ginny Lloyd, 1984-1988 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Cincinnati, Ohio: Michael Lowe, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Rohnert Park, California: Tim Mancusi, 1992-1995, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 59-60)
    - Amarillo, Texas: Stanley Marsh, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Fremont, California: Misery Research Center, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Dallas, Texas: Modern Realism, 1984-1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - New York, New York: Barbara Moore, 1981-1993 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Rochester, New York: Robert C. Morgan, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - North Valley Stream, New York: National Stampagraphic, 1983-1995 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - New York, New York: Valery Oisteanu, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Chicago, Illinois: Ashley Parker Owens, 1992-1995, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 68-69)
    - Houston, Texas: Tom Pack, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Bellingham, Washington: J. C. Palmer (a.k.a. Rudi Rubberoid), 1987-1995, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 71-75)
    - Garland, Texas: Julie Paquette (a.k.a. e-poste facto), 1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Boulder, Colorado: Julle Peasley, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Iowa City, Iowa: Stephen Perkins, 1991-1995, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 78-81)
    - New York, New York: Clive Phillpot, 1988-1994, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 82-83)
    - New York, New York: Carlo Pittore (Charles Stanley), 1983-1991, (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 84-88)
    - Eureka, California: Ms. Pitts, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Austin, Texas: Daniel Plunkett, 1982-1995, (7 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-7)
    - New York, New York: Ed M. Plunkett, 1973-1985, undated, (7 folders) (Box 7, Folder 8-10)
    - Belfast, Maine: Bern Porter, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - New York, New York: Printed Matter, Inc., 1981-1992, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 12-13)
    - San Francisco, California: Private World, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Tarpon Springs, Florida: John Pyros (Epistolary Stud Farm), 1986-1989, undated, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15-18)
    - Chapel Hill, North Carolina: Ram Cell, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Greenfield, Massachusetts: Steve Random, 1983-1984, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 20-21)
    - Sausalito, California: Howard Reingold, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - San Francisco, California: Robert RoCola, 1984-1993, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 23-26)
    - Miami Beach, Florida: Ruth and Marvin Sackner, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Metuchen, New Jersey: Scarecrow Press, 1989-1994, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 28-33)
    - Lansing, Michigan: Carol Schneck, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Fresno, California: E. Z. Smith, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Culver City, California: Barbara Solarz, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Berkeley, California: Norman Solomon (a.k.a. Mr. Postcards), 1990-1994, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 37-39)
    - Dallas, Texas: Alan Sondheim, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Corvalis, Oregon: Roberta Sperling, 1983-1993, undated, (2 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 41-42)
    - Los Angeles, California: Lon Spiegelman, 1982-1992, undated, (8 folders; oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 43-50)
    - Newton Centre, Massachusetts: Jonathan Stangroom, 1991-1992, (Oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Minneapolis, Minnesota: State of Being (Reid Wood), 1987-1994 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Minneapolis, Minnesota: Roslyn Stendahl (a.k.a. Gummiglot), 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Oatman, Arizona: Carol Stetser, 1987-1993 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Stamford, Connecticut: Lowry Thompson, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - San Francisco, California: Darlene Tong, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Burbank, California: John Tostdada (a.k.a. Johnny Tostdada or Oh Boy Mail Art), 1985-1992, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 57-59)
    - Des Moines, Iowa: Fred Truck, 1980-1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 60-61)
    - Dallas, Texas: Bob Wade (a.k.a. Daddy-O), 1982-1992, undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Madison, Wisconsin: Liz Was, undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Hanover, Maryland: Nanci Waterman, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Lebanon, New Hampshire: Chuck Welch (a.k.a. Crackerjack Kid), 1982-1995, undated, (14 folders) (Box 7, Folder 65-78)
  - Letters Sent by John Held, Jr., 1990, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 79-81)
  - Letters Sent by John Held, Jr., 1991, (11 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-11)
  - Letters Sent by John Held, Jr., 1992, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 12-14)
  - Letters Sent by John Held, Jr., 1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Letters Sent by John Held, Jr., 1994 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Letters Sent by John Held, Jr., 1995 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Letters Sent by John Held, Jr., 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Letters Sent by John Held, Jr., 1999-2008, (Oversized material housed in Box 10) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Letters Exchanged with Steve Durland, "The High Performance Letters," 1991 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Letters from Others Concerning the Annotated Bibliography, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Notebook: "Key to the Collection," 2008, 2008, from Box 1, Folder 27 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Letter from Argentina (La Plata): Graciela Marx, 1988, from Box 1, Folder 28 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Letter from Belgium (Wellen): Guy Bleus, 1989, from Box 1, Folder 40 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Letter from Canada (Québec): Jean Claude Gagnon, 1994, from Box 1, Folder 76 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Letter from England (London): Dictionary of Art, 1994, from Box 1, Folder 14 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Letter from Germany (Halle): Guillermo Deissler, 1989, from Box 2, Folder 64 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Letter from Holland (Maastricht): Rod Summers, 1992, from Box 2, Folder 107 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Three Oversized Letters from Italy (Brescia): Guglielmo Cavellini, 1984, from Box 3, Folder 19 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Letter from Italy (Salerno): Salvatore De Rosa, 1988, from Box 3, Folder 22 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Two Oversized Letters from Italy (Milan): Ruggero Maggi, 1990-1991, from Box 3, Folder 26 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Five Oversized Letters from Japan (Osaka): Ryosuke Cohen, 1985-1999, from Box 3, Folders 30, 31, and 33 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Four Oversized Letters from Japan (Amagasaki): Mayumi Handa, 1990-1991, from Box 3, Folder 35 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Eleven Oversized Letters from Japan (Nishinomiya): Shozo Shimamoto, 1983-1994, undated, from Box 3, Folders 40-44 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Letter from Mexico (Tepoztlan): David Zack, 1987, from Box 3, Folder 56 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Letter from Sweden (Stockholm): Peter Meyer, 1985, from Box 3, Folder 74 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Letter from Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (Tartu, Estonia): Ilmar Kruusamae, 1990, from Box 3, Folder 95 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Letter from the United States of America (San Antonio, Texas): Al Ackerman, 1986, from Box 4, Folder 38 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Letter from the United States of America (Madison, Wisconsin): Miekal And, 1985, from Box 4, Folder 47 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Letter from the United States of America (Seattle, Washington): C. T. Chew, 1991, from Box 5, Folder 28 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Letter from the United States of America (San Francisco, California): William Gaglione (a.k.a. Daddaland), 1991, from Box 5, Folder 71 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Letter from the United States of America (Rifton, New York): Jennifer Huebert, 1992, from Box 6, Folder 22 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Letter from the United States of America (New York, New York): John P. Jacobs (a.k.a. Hype), 1984, from Box 6, Folder 31 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Letter from the United States of America (Utica, New York): Jonas Kover (a.k.a. J. K. Post), 1993, from Box 6, Folder 48 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Letter from the United States of America (Corvalis, Oregon): Roberta Sperling, undated, from Box 7, Folder 41 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Two Oversized Letters from the United States of America (Los Angeles, California): Lon Spiegelman, 1984-1985, from Box 7, Folders 43 and 44 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Letter from the United States of America (Newton Centre, Massachusetts): Jonathan Stangroom, 1991, from Box 7, Folder 51 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Envelope from John Held, Jr., 2008, from Box 8, Folder 19 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Letter from Japan (Osaka): Seiko Miyazaki, 1988, from Box 3, Folder 38 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
- Art Work, 1985-2007, Series 4:; (Box 8; 12 folders)
  Art work consists of mail art postage stamps: pseudo-postage stamps (artistamps) designed by miscellaneous participants in the international mail art network.
  - Mail Art Postage Stamps (Box 8)
    - Unidentified Artists, 1995-2006, undated, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 22-24)
    - Vittore Baroni (Italy); Keith Bates (England); Boog; M. B. Corbett (a.k.a. Tensetendoned) (U.S.A.), 1992-1993, undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Dazar (a.k.a. Omahaha) (U.S.A.); Mike Dickau and John Held, Jr.; Dogfish (Robert Rudine) (U.S.A.), 2003-2004, undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Harley Francis (a.k.a. Terra Candella) (U.S.A.); L. Z. Francke; Hans Ruedi Fricker (Switzerland); Arturo G, 1987-1993, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - John Held, Jr.; Diane Perin Hock; Jocelyn; Eleanor Kent, 1985-1996, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Peter Küstermann (a.k.a. Peter Netmail) (Germany); Tim Mancusi (U.S.A.); Mary V. Marsh; Eddie Nero, 1992-2004, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Julle Peasley (U.S.A.); Michael W. Phillips, Jr.; Carlo Pittore (U.S.A.); Ram Cell (U.S.A.), 1994-2007, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Robert RoCola (U.S.A.); Shozo Shimamoto (Japan); Jenny Soup; D. C. Spalding, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Sticker Dude; Jonathan Stangroom (U.S.A.); John Tostada (a.k.a. Johnny Tostadada and Oh Boy Mail Art) (U.S.A.), 1997, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Chuck Welch (a.k.a. Crackerjack Kid ) (U.S.A.); Reid Wood (a.k.a. State of Being) (U.S.A.); Gerardo Yepiz, 1987-1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Interview Transcripts, 1977-1995, Series 5:; (Box 8; 7 folders)
  Transcripts are of interviews conducted by John Held, Jr. with Al Ackerman, John Cage, Ray Johnson, Allan Kaprow, and interviews with Held, Picasso Gaglione, and Milan Knizak. There is also an interview with Held conducted by Ruud Janssen.
  - "Illogical as an Instructive Process: An Interview with Ray Johnson" by John Held, Jr., 1977 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - "An Interview with John Cage" by John Held, Jr., 1987 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - "An Interview with Allan Kaprow" by John Held, Jr., 1988 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - "Al Ackerman Interviewed by John Held, Jr." for ND Magazine, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - "Factsheet Fake Picabia: A Conversation with Picasso Gaglione and John Held, Jr.," 1994 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - "An Aktual Conversation Between Milan Knizak and John Held, Jr.," 1994 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - "Traveling Art Mail: Interview of John Held, Jr. (Dallas, Texas) by Ruud Janssen (Tilberg, Holland)," 1995 (Box 8, Folder 40)
- Writings, 1984-2000, Series 6:; (Box 8; 51 folders)
  Writings by John Held, Jr. consist of catalog essays, miscellaneous essays, bibliographies, miscellaneous box set texts, and miscellaneous typescripts.
  Writings are arranged by type and chronologically thereafter.
  - Catalog Essays (Box 8)
    - "Andrew Tisma: Spiritual Sculptor;" "The Caustic Jelly Post Portraits of buZ blurr," undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - "The First International Female Artistamp Exhibition;" "The Formidable Blue Stamp of Yves Klein," undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - "Guy Bleus: Global Administration;" "James W. Felter: Artistamp Activist," undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - "Learning from Friedman: Rubber Stramp Activity;" "May Wilson: Grandmother to the Avant-Garde," undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Catalog Essay: "The Open world of Dobrica Kamperelic," undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Catalog Essay: "Robert Watts: The Complete Postage Stamp Sheets, 1961-1986," undated (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Catalog Essay: "The Rubber Stamps of Ray Johnson," undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - "The Sugar-Coated Bullets of Pawel Petasz;" "The Tam Rubberstamp-Archive of Ruud Janssen," undated (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - "The Treatment of Vision: Arman's Cachets," undated (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - "Yugoslavian Networkers: Towards the Open World on an Unpaved Super Highway," undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous Essays (Box 8)
    - "An Introduction to Faux Post;" "A Ray Johnson Miscellany," undated (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - "Architecture (for Guy Bleus);" "Archives and Memory;" "Archiving and Documenting the Underground," undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - "Big Brother Meets Art Brut: Photocopier Works by Artists;" "buZ blurr: Caustic Jelly Post;" "Collaging Information: The Artist, The Librarian, The Artist/Librarian," undated (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - "Dada Never Preached: the Underground Heroism of Perry 'Indian Ralph' Mancusi;" "Do-It-Yourself Stamp Culture;" "Heart of a Networker," undated (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - "Impressions in Flux;" "Justice, Human Rights, and the Printed Word (Eastern European, Yugoslavian, and Cuban Alternative Publishing," undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - "The Last Shadow Performance;" "Mail Art at the End of the Century;" "Mailfestas and Marathons: Cross Currents in Contemporary Mail Art," undated (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - "The Most Famous Unknown Artist" (Ray Johnson); "Notes from the Rim: Interviews, Travel Diaries, and Essays;" "Open World of Netland;" "Picasso Gaglione: Black Mail Post," undated (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - "Ray Johnson and the Mail Art Show;" "Resolutions of the Networker Writers Congress;" "The Shadow Project: A Collaboration Between the Mail Art Network and Peace Activists in Contemplation of an Uncertain Age," undated (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - "The Sound of One Sandal Flapping" (Sanford Berman); "Soviet Impressions: Rubber Stamps in the U.S.S.R.;" "Surrealist Digest: The Rubber Stamps of E. M. Plunkett," undated (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - "They Will Go Underground;" "Tim Mancusi: The Complete Artist Postage Stamps;" "Undercurrents: A Keynote Address," undated (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - "Unexpected Communication: The Mail Art of Piermario Ciani;" "(What is) International Networker Culture (Anyway)?;" " What is the Social Responsibility of the Artist?: A Catalog," undated (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - "Where the Secret is Hidden (a Translation and Commentary)" by Serge Segay, Lloyd Dunn, and John Held, Jr., undated (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - "Guglielmo Achille Cavellini;" "From Moticos to Mail Art," 1990 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - "Postal Static: Mailbox Magic and Madness," 1990 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - "Artist Statement by John Held, Jr.: Decentralized World-Wide Networker Congress;" "Decentralized World-Wide Networker Congress," 1992 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - "One Day in the Life of the Eternal Network: (Nov. 10, 1972);" "Crossing the Cactus Curtain: Politics and Isolation Test and the Commitment of Latin American Artists," 1992 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - "Open World/People in Bondage: A Performance by John Held, Jr. and Alice Lee Regarding the Yugoslavian Situation;" "Artistamps by Joki," 1993 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - "Archivist of the Underground: Jean Brown, 1911-1994;" "Picasso of the Underground: Bill Gaglione Flutters on the Margins of the Art World Helping to Create a Thriving Alternative Culture;" "Do-It-Yourself Postage Stamps," 1993 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - "Bunny Dead: The Mysterious Life and Death of Ray Johnson and the Rise of the New York Correspondence School of Art;" "Networking: Origin of Terminology in Mail Art for Eternal Network by Chuck Welch," 1995 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - "Notes Toward a History of Artistamps," 1996 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - "Dada to DIY: The Rise of Alternative Cultures in the Twentieth Century," 1998 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - "Debate on Mail Art (in Response to Clemente Padin);" "In Search of the Photograph that Kills," 1999 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - "Before Punk and Zines: Bay Area Dada," 1999 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - "A History of Rubber Stamp Art," 1999 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - "Chaos and the Network (for Ruggero Maggi;" "Across Vanishing Borders: Mail Art and the Internet," 2000 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - "The Fake Picabia Bros. 1992-2000," 2000 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - "Julie Hagan Bloch: Eraser Carving for the John Held, Jr. Papers, Archives of American Art;" "Obvious Front 'Industrial Strength Art,'" 2000 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Bibliographies (Box 8)
    - "Artist Postage Stamps: A Selected Bibliography," undated (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - "Stamp Art Gallery Store Publications," undated (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - "Bay Area Dada, 1970-1984: An Annotated Bibliography," 1984 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - "FeMail Art: An Annotated Bibliography," 1991 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - "Networker Congress 1992: An Annotated Bibliography," 1991 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - "Preparing for Networker Congress: An Annotated Bibliography," 1992 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - "California College of the Arts and Crafts Course Bibliography," 1997 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Miscellaneous Box Set Texts, undated (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Box Set Texts: "Faux Fluxus/West Edition;" "Ken Friedman;" "Tim Mancusi," 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Miscellaneous Typescripts (Box 8)
    - "Mail Art Performance Party: A Proposal for Neofest at Sushi, San Diego, California," 1991 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - "Stamp Francisco Networker Congress Report," 1992 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - "Entries for the Standard Catalogue (As Submitted to the Bugmaster General)," 1993 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - "Faux Post" NEA Application, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - "Book Reviews by John Held, Jr.," 1997-2000 (Box 8, Folder 91)
- Project and Event Files, 1982-2000, Series 7:; (Box 8; 11 folders)
  This series consists of files concerning projects, tours, lectures, and exhibitions with which John Held, Jr. was involved.
  - Modern Realism, 1982-2000, undated, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 92-94)
  - Los Angeles Tour, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - South America Tour, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Lecture at Victoria and Albert Museum, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Dadawerke: A Retrospective Performance History, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Exhibition L'Art du Tampon (Rubber Stamp) and Loans to the Musée de la Poste, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Dallas Retrospective, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - The Stamp Art Gallery, 1995-1997, undated (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Exhibition Faux Post, San Francisco Center for the Book, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 102)
- Printed Material, 1989-2000, Series 8:; (Box 8; 11 folders)
  Printed material consists primarily of computer-generated printouts of periodicals, a newsletter, exhibition catalogs, and press releases concerning mail art.
  - Periodical Printouts (Box 8)
    - Bibliozone (#1-8), 1992 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Bibliozone (#9-19), 1993 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Bibliozone (#20-27), 1994 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Bibliozone (#28-42), 1995 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Bibliozone (#43-54), 1996 (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Bibliozone (#55, 57, 58), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - Bibliozone (#60-66), 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - Artistampzine (#1), 2000 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Newsletter Re: The E-Mail-Art and Internet-Art Manifesto by E-Pêle-Mêle, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1989-1996, undated (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Press Releases, 1990-1999, undated (Box 8, Folder 113)